# Aurélio Carlos Prado Silva

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER · INFRASTRUCTURE AND NETWORK ADMIN · DEVOPS

Presidente Prudente, SP, Brazil

□ (+55) 18 99709-0943 | 🗷 aureliocarlosps@gmail.com | 🏕 lelolabs.com | 🖸 lelinho | 🛅 aurelio-c-a9621b1b9

## Summary.

Master in Computer Science with emphasis on database, data streams, microservices and event-driven programming, specialist in Computer Networks. More than 15 years of career with experience both in systems development and in network infrastructure and administration of servers and systems. Easy adaptation to new technologies, languages, frameworks and methodologies. Flexibility when working in different IT areas, always using knowledge from previous experiences.

### Education

#### M.S. degree in Computer Science

Presidente Prudente, SP

UNESP - Universidade Estadual Paulista

2021

- · SQLStreamify: middleware based on microservices architecture providing real-time data stream reading transactions in legacy DBMSs
- Emphasis on database, data streams, microservices-based architecture, containers, microservices, and event-driven programming
- · Advisor: Dr. Ronaldo Celso Messias Correa

#### **Postgraduate - Specialist in Computer Networks**

Presidente Prudente. SP

ESAB - ESCOLA SUPERIOR ABERTA DO BRASIL

2016

· Focus on theoretical and practical foundations of computer networks.

#### **Bachelor of Science, Computer Science**

Presidente Prudente, SP

UNESP - Universidade Estadual Paulista

2012

- · Conclusion paper: Study on the implementation and operation of IPv6 and Mobile IPv6 protocols in the FCT/UNESP network
- · Advisor: Dr. Milton Hirokazo Shimabukuro

#### **Computer Technician Course**

Presidente Prudente, SP

COLÉGIO BRAGA MELLO 2003

· Course focused on systems development.

# **Experience**

#### **UNESP - Universidade Estadual Paulista**

Presidente Prudente, SP

Infrastructure Administrator - Servers, Networks and Systems

2009 - current

- Several network services administration and deployment (DNS, DHCP, Web Servers Apache, NGINX, Tomcat, pfSense, IPAM, Zabbix, Nagios...)
- Server virtualization experience (VMware, Xen, KVM) including the entire infrastructure migration from VMware hypervisor to Xen
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Services and applications containerization experience (Docker, Docker-compose, Portainer)} \ \ several \ services \ migration \ from \ VMs \ to \ containers$
- Network infrastructure management (switches, routers, access points)
- Equipment and services monitoring (Zabbix, Grafana, Prometheus)
- Python, Shell script, Ansible automation
- Some experience in management, acting as IT Director Substitute.

Colégio Braga Mello Presidente Prudente, SP

COMPUTER TECHNICIAN - DEVELOPMENT AND INFRASTRUCTURE MANAGER

2008 - 2009

- Academic, Financial and Payroll Control Systems development.
- Linux and Windows Server servers deployment and administration.
- · Databases administration (MySQL, PostgreSQL)

#### MTTEC - Automação Industrial

Presidente Prudente, SP

TRAINEE - DEVELOPMENT

2007 - 2008

 Participation in the development team of ERP projects, Commercial Automation, TEF (Electronic Fund Transfer), among others. Primarily using Visual Basic and PostgreSQL databases. ASP.Net, Java and PHP experience.

Global Automação Presidente Prudente, SP

TRAINEE - DEVELOPMENT

2003 - 2007

 Working on development project team for Commercial Automation, Gas Station Management System, among others. Working with Visual Basic and MySQL databases.

#### Agência Brasileira de Correios e Telégrafos

Presidente Prudente, SP

Trainee 2003 - 2003

· Computers and network maintenance. Database implementation for company internal use.

Yázigi - Escola de Idiomas Presidente Prudente, SP

ESTÁGIO 2001 - 2002

· Network, systems, machines and website maintenance. And Computer Lab supervision.

# Extracurricular Projects \_\_

#### cTwittLike (web and iOS App)

Google AppEngine, Python, Swift,

App Store 2009 - 2014

FREE TIME PROJECT

• Application with the objective of see Twitter like someone else.

- First developed in Python and run on Google AppEngine.
- · Covered by Mashable, Engadget, Tecnoblog, among others, causing great traffic in which I had to work on project scale to meet the requests.
- Years later the idea was developed in Swift and made available as an iOS app.

#### Reminder Widget: for Evernote Reminders (iOS app)

Objective-C

2017

FREE TIME PROJECT

2015

- · iOS Application created to supply the lack of a widget (better than the official one at the time) for Evernote reminders.
- Developed right on the release of iOS widget development.
- · Details on AppAdvice.

Ganhei? (iOS app)

Swift, Node.js, AWS, App Store

FREE TIME PROJECT

• Application to register games and check results of Mega-Sena (brazilian lottery).

- · Project developed in Swift with backend in Node.js to send notifications when the result of the draw is released.
- OCR use to recognize numbers played when reading bet ticket for automatic registration.
- Covered by MacMagazine as application suggestion.

# Skills.

**Programming** Python, JAVA, Swift, Visual Basic, C#, ASP.Net, PHP, Javascript, Node.js, Flask, Django, Hugo, LaTeX,

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Event Driven Programming, Microservices Architecture, Systems Dev. Methodologies

**Databases** Relational and NoSQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLServer, Redis, MongoDB, Firebase)

**Message Queuing** Stream Data Processing (RabbitMQ, ActiveMQ, MQTT)

**Network Infrastructure** Configuration and Administration of routers, switches, APs, firewalls (Cisco, HP, Aruba, 3com, Dell, pfSense...)

**Servers Administration** Linux, FreeBSD e Windows - Python, Shell Script and Ansible automation

> Virtualization VMware, Xen, KVM

Observability Zabbix, Grafana, Prometheus

**Containers** Docker, docker-compose, Swarm, Kubernetes, Portainer

**CI/CD** Git, Github Actions, Gitlab

IaC Ansible, Terraform

Cloud Amazon (AWS, EC2, S3, Route53)

Languages Native portuguese, advanced english, basic spanish

# Certifications

2021 Gitlab Certified Associate